Contact

ericphewitt@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ericphewitt (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

HTML

Python (Programming Language)
Agile Project Management

Certifications

Google Project Management Certificate

Florida Bar Exam

Finance and Quantitative Modeling for Analysts

Lean Six Sigma White Belt Certification

Publications

Climate Change and Corporate Profitability: The Effects of Greenhouse Gasses and Sustainability Strategies on Stock Price Performance

An Argument for Dualism

Sivolella v. Axa Equitable Life Ins. Co., Civil Action No. 11-cv-4194 (PGS)(DEA), 2016 U.S. Dist. LEXIS 113822 (D.N.J. Aug. 25, 2016)

Eric Hewitt

Veteran | Consultant | Project / Program Manager | Investment Banking and Financial Services | Tech

Miami, Florida, United States

Summary

I am a multi-faceted professional with strong financial expertise incorporating sustainability and modern ecological economic theory. A high-performing individual, I maintain a respect towards compliance, strategic consulting, a passion for justice, and a humanitarian focus as shown through my military, professional, and educational experiences. I have intellectual curiosity, and enjoy solving complex problems in high-pace environments, leading teams, project or program management, strategy, mentoring, research, real estate, entrepreneurship, data analysis, litigation, critical thinking, valuations, sustainability, and investing in the markets. During my down time I play chess, learn something new, hit some tennis balls, fiddle with amateur astronomy, and travel.

Inquiries: erichewitt@alumni.harvard.edu

Technical skills: Python, CSS, SQL, HTML, financial modeling in Excel, R, Tableau, certified in Project/Program management, legal analysis, certified in Agile/Scrum, data analysis, statistical analysis, certified in Six Sigma

Experience

Eric Hewitt LLC

Owner

February 2017 - Present (6 years)

 Manage private equity real estate investments and oversee real estate operations

Berkshire Hathaway HomeServices EWM Realty Real Estate Consultant April 2021 - Present (1 year 10 months)

Miami-Fort Lauderdale Area

• Licensed in 2000 (PA), 2021 (FL)

Victor Tech Co-Founder, Chief Financial Officer 2018 - 2019 (1 year)

Chicago, Illinois, United States

- Co-founded a mobile app start-up to serve the veteran population, designed/ implemented the strategy for the UX and minimum viable product
- Business plan finalist at Bunker Labs and the Civic Accelerator
- Created a marketing strategy, financial documents (three statement financial model in excel), and helped define corporate strategy as a management consultant
- Mentored and managed two finance interns out of the seven hired
- Designed the financial portion of the pitch deck and presented it to venture capitalists in San Francisco and DC - managed capital raising efforts

FINRA (Financial Industry Regulatory Authority)
Legal Extern - Enforcement Division
August 2018 - December 2018 (5 months)

Chicago, Illinois, United States

- Performed litigation preparation/litigation support by researching securities case law and wrote legal memorandums to clarify respondents' potential defenses allowing FINRA senior attorneys to have critical information on hand during hearings
- Created the sanctions guidelines for securities regulatory compliance cases dealing with financial misconduct and criminality
- Pioneered a new legal research procedure for requesting research projects
- Drafted settlement agreements; supported & attended depositions

United States District Court for the District of New Jersey Judicial Law Clerk 2016 - 2016 (less than a year)

Trenton, New Jersey, United States

- Drafted bench memos evaluating the credibility of character witnesses for a Federal Judge reducing the time it takes for him to review a 30-day trial's deposition transcripts
- Attended and discussed settlement negotiations, oral arguments, and sentencing hearings learning the thought processes of the bench
- Reviewed evidence submissions and prepared legal opinions on legal standards of federal law which were used in a published opinion
- Researched legal precedence (Gartenburg Factors) regarding excessive fees relating to the Investment Company Act of 1940, understanding the fiduciary

responsibilities of board members and how they are applied to a case involving excessive fees pursuant to Section 36(b)

Harvard Management Company High-Yield Credit Desk 2014 - 2014 (less than a year) Boston, Massachusetts, United States

- Evaluated and presented daily credit risk and foreign exchange reports for the trader and PM of a billion dollar credit portfolio, allowing the trader to understand the implications of the day's trades
- Entered all trades for the desk and traded \$50MM-\$100MM in credit derivatives per day with 100% accuracy, freeing up the trader's time to do imperative research
- Executed a nightly profit-and-loss report for the desk calculating all positions traded and portfolio risk for the upcoming trading day using Murex and Bloomberg AIM
- Hedged FX positions to eliminate portfolio risk

Offices of Congressman Stephen Lynch Congressional Aide January 2013 - May 2013 (5 months) Boston, Massachusetts, United States

- Handled constituent issues during the Senate race against Ed Markey
- Reviewed applications to the service academies, selected and presented the best candidates for Congressional approval

Morgan Stanley Associate 2008 - 2009 (1 year)

- Analyzed and presented potential investments and created portfolios that consistently outperformed the market benchmarks
- Designed pitch books, provided market color, analyzed portfolios, recommended investment asset-allocations, managed investments
- Analyzed 10Ks and 10Qs, completed equity research, evaluated investments
- Created an investment asset-allocation proposal that resulted in a new \$10 million dollar client
- · Passed the Series 7, 31, 66

U.S. Army and Army National Guard Noncomissioned Officer (Program Manager) August 2004 - May 2007 (2 years 10 months) Page 3 of 6

United States

- Program manager tasked with mentoring and training 30-40 soldiers in the newly established 56th Stryker Brigade Combat Team as a 19D, Cav Scout
- Assisted in investigations of incidents, offenses, and allegations of criminality as a Special Agent

Units:

56th Stryker Brigade Combat Team, 28th Infantry Division, 104th Calvary (RSTA)

Criminal Investigation Division Command

BlackRock Business System Analyst 2007 - 2007 (less than a year)

New York, NY

- Ran risk analysis applications in Aladdin on a \$10 trillion asset portfolio and conveyed results to portfolio managers
- Analyzed compliance and regulatory guidelines for external portfolios and created system flags for the client's traders in Aladdin

U.S. Department of the Treasury

Project Manager

2006 - 2007 (1 year)

Washington D.C. Metro Area

- Project manager tasked with the initiative of transforming a division in OMB to paperless invoice processing
- Reduced payment processing time by 33% using \$100,000 in funds already allocated for the department

Rothschild & Co

Investment Banking Summer Analyst

2006 - 2006 (less than a year)

New York, NY

- Analyst on the \$519 million dollar sale of Cornell Companies, Inc. to the PE firm Veritas Capital
- Designed pitch books, entered deal data, reviewed and analyzed SEC filings
- Computed the transaction comps, trading comps, discounted cash flow, and cost of capital for the deal
- Valued companies and modeled mergers and aquisitions transactions in excel

United States Marine Corps

Noncommissioned Officer (Project / Program manager; Management Consultant)

August 1999 - August 2004 (5 years 1 month)

United States

- Led an infantry squad in a constantly changing fast-paced environment, selected/inspired/influenced 12 direct reports, and was a force-multiplier while on active duty (~ 3 years and 2 deployments)
- Optimized and coordinated cross-functional teams from intelligence, interpreters, weapons co, sigintel, psyops, local police and political leadership/ assets
- Consulted with C-level officers (field grade) about their unit's complex projects/programs, used problem-solving abilities and planned, presented, and executed mission-critical operations in Iraq, debriefed field-grade officers after successful implementation of an agreed-upon strategy
- Awarded the Combat Action Ribbon (CAR), Presidential Unit Citation, two bronze campaign stars, five medals, and two Meritorious Masts for operational effectiveness and leadership skills

Units:

2/25 E Co. Squad Leader/Platoon Guide
2/25 H&S Co. Surveillance and Target Acquisition (STA) Plt. (special operations capable); S2
I Marine Expeditionary Force - Iraqi Freedom, 2003

Education

Notre Dame Law School Juris Doctor - JD

Harvard University

Master in Liberal Arts (ALM) - EXT & GSA, Sustainability

University of Notre Dame - Mendoza College of Business Master of Business Administration - MBA

Georgetown University

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration (BSBA), Finance, Management

PDX Code Guild

Full Stack Web/Software Developer · (November 2022 - April 2023)